♪
[distant chatter]
[CLINE] We're way less efficient
as a duo!
Damn!
[Reiss sighs]
[CLINE]
I thought that Heal Mushrooms
were supposed
to be a guaranteed drop,
but we killed four Matango
and still didn't see
a single one!
Maybe Ruche's Lady Luck
was doing something after all.
If you hadn't
given her the boot,
things might have gone
in our favor, you know?
[Cline scoffs] Coincidence.
She could've stayed
if she hadn't demanded a cut
from selling
the Blood-Soaked Sword.
So what are you saying?
Invite her back?
Listen, Reiss.
I have my dignity
to preserve here.
I can't invite Ruche back
after everything I said to her.
Given the choice, I'd rather die
than ask her for anything.
[sighs]
[CLINE] Fortunately,
we've got plenty of money
from selling that sword.
There's no need to worry.
We can take our time
finding someone
with the right skills,
even if they're low-level.
[REISS] Mm.
[ADVENTURER 1] That dungeon?
Not a D or C Rank?
Huh?
[curious chatter]
[ADVENTURER 2] Where is he?
I can't see him.
What's this?
I'm guessing
maybe someone defeated
a high-level monster
or something.
-Him again?
-Huh?
Patchwork Bears? Really?
[ADVENTURER 3]
I've seen that guy before.
A newly minted E Rank and F Rank
somehow managed to do all that?
They beat the Angel's Playbox?
The recommended level is 50!
[gasps]
-[REISS] No way.
-[gasps]
Those two did what now?!
[♪ opening theme song playing]
[ELYMAS] We weren't trying
to beat the dungeon.
It's just that
while we were there,
the Dreamlord attacked us
while it was wandering.
As for proof,
two other adventurers
were involved.
You can ask them.
Very well, then.
I'll confirm with them both.
The city's been offering
a bounty on the Angel's Playbox.
If you defeated it, it's yours.
[Ruche giggles]
[ELYMAS] Bounties
are sometimes placed
on dungeons located
near cities and villages.
Monsters tend to emerge
from dungeons that have been
left alone for too long.
And that can lead to all sorts
of chaos
and disasters in the area.
A dungeon's
recommended level depends
on the region
in which it appears.
But no matter
where it's located,
there's always
a clear separation
between low
and high-level areas.
Some believe it's caused by
the mana flowing in the region,
while others say
it's the will of Alzuhrohs,
and beyond human comprehension.
But to be honest,
this is just conjecture
and nothing
is truly known for certain.
High-level adventurers
tend to operate out of cities
adjacent to where
dangerous dungeons appear.
The pay is better,
and it does more
to serve the kingdom.
With high-level fighters
being drawn elsewhere,
no one in Rondalm
could have beaten
the Angel's Playbox.
The mayor put a bounty on it,
fearing the dungeon
would be ignored
and unleash monsters.
Oh. So the dungeon
really had a bounty?
I can honestly say that
I wasn't expecting that.
-How much is it?
-[gasps]
It's 10 million gold.
[all gasp]
Ten million?!
Wow, 10 million gold, huh?
Well, that will surely
come in handy.
[RUCHE]
I know I should be happy,
but my head is still spinning
from all those drops
we picked up in the dungeon.
[Cline gasps]
Was it Lady Luck?
It helped those two
get a rare drop
from a Dreamlord
meant for a level-50 party?
That Elymas guy,
he scooped up Ruche
as soon as he figured out
she had Lady Luck.
They just scored a huge payday,
but they seem pretty unfazed.
If anyone else
raked in 10 million gold,
they'd be jumping for joy!
So, that begs the question,
how much money have they made?
Also, you'll now be promoted
from Rank E to Rank D
in accordance with
guild regulations, Mr. Elymas.
Ms. Ruche, you'll be jumping
from Rank F to Rank D.
Wait, what? Ruche is Rank D?
[REISS]
It's not clear how she did it.
But she obviously rose
beyond our reach
-at some point.
-She can't be.
-Hmm? Hey, Cline?
-That's just insane.
-[Cline grunts]
-[REISS] Hey! What the...
-Then that means--
-[Cline yells] Ruche!
I'm so sorry!
It was wrong of me
to kick you out!
Please come back!
Do it, and we'll split the money
from the Blood-Soaked Sword
evenly with you!
'Kay?
[gasps]
[groans]
[sighs] Oof.
[Ruche sputters]
Ruche, let's go.
I think we should celebrate.
-[RUCHE] Right.
-[gasps]
Stop! Hold on a second!
Can you at least hear me out
before you leave?
Um, I mean--
[gasps]
No, please. I wanted to say...
Yikes.
[♪ merry music playing]
[RUCHE]
This place just looks expensive!
[ELYMAS] We earned it.
[WAITRESS] Thank you so much
for waiting, sir and lady.
[ELYMAS] I don't know about you,
but I certainly
wasn't expecting the promotions
or the bounty today.
A couple of happy accidents.
[whimpers]
♪
[chuckles softly]
Going up to Rank D
raised our skill point cap.
Now it's at 45.
The Fang of Smoldering Insanity
skillbook is within reach too.
But how should we
farm money next?
Hmm.
Um. Hey, Mr. Elymas? You okay?
Oh. I'm sorry.
We came here to celebrate.
And that's the only thing
I should be focused on.
Yeah! Exactly!
So let's have some fun then.
Okay?
[BOTH] Cheers!
[both chugging]
[squeals excitedly]
I've wanted to come
to this place for so long!
And now?
I'm here.
I've always dreamed of eating
at the Alchemist King's Stove,
Mr. Elymas!
I told myself that once
I'd made it as an adventurer,
this is where I'd come
with my party.
I do have to admit,
I always imagined
I'd be sitting here
with Mr. Cline
and Ms. Reiss, though.
Did you forget that I always
paid you the bare minimum?
You horrible ingrate!
[scoffs] You certainly didn't!
Uh. [laughing nervously]
[gasps] How does their king crab
and black truffle sauce pie
cost 8,000 gold?!
I didn't think
it'd be this expensive.
Wow, and I nearly ordered one.
-Mr. Elymas!
-[chuckles softly]
Don't order anything
from this page!
Let's just look for some entrees
that are under 4,000 gold!
Could I have one king crab
and black truffle sauce pie,
please?
-What?!
-[WAITRESS] Yes, sir.
Wait. Are you sure about this?
[whimpering]
[ELYMAS] It must not have
sunk in yet.
[WAITRESS] Your king crab
and black truffle sauce pie.
-Enjoy.
-[gasps in awe]
[Ruche gasps eagerly]
[exclaiming]
[ELYMAS] It's really good!
[Ruche sighs contentedly]
I'm in heaven!
This is good too!
[Elymas laughs] Glad to hear it.
We really need to discuss
how to split all the loot
and gold we earned.
First off, do you want
to use the skillbook?
Because I think
it'd be a good idea
for you to have
Intermediate Wind Magic.
Hold on,
so you're not going to use it?
No. Not that it's bad,
but I'd like to aim
much higher than that,
and I've already got
a build in mind.
-Well, I won't use it either.
-Y-- You sure?
If you have this skill tree,
Ruche,
you'll have no problem
finding a party for a while.
[RUCHE] Hmm.
That would mean
working with others
who don't have
the same goals as you and I.
I mean, I want to aim higher,
just like you.
Besides, it'd be sad
to say goodbye so soon.
Well, don't you agree?
[gasps, chuckles softly]
In that case,
I guess we'll sell it.
To be honest,
that'll help us out a lot.
Were you short
on money or something?
Not anymore.
And after subtracting
various expenses,
we earned about 57 million gold.
Just hearing
that amount makes me dizzy.
We'll do an 80/20 split,
so you get 46 million gold.
Wait, what?!
And as for me, I'll end up
with 11 million gold.
Come on! If we form a party,
you're not gonna regret it!
So, what do you say?
Would an 80/20 split
work for you?!
I meant that you would
be getting the 80%, of course!
Wait, you mean you were serious
about that offer?!
[gasps] Um, Ruche, settle down.
You're making a scene.
Everyone's staring at us.
Is 80/20 not good enough?
No, I'm sor-- No, wait!
There's no way
I could ever accept
an amount like that, Mr. Elymas!
Geez, how did you even come up
with this 80/20 thing anyway?
Um, it's a pretty common thing
for deals
to involve splits like that.
Oh, yeah, really?!
In what universe
does that ever happen?
You can't seriously expect me
to just accept 40 million gold!
I'm thankful to you
for helping me raise my level,
but you think I'm some
gold-hoarding goon, don't you?!
[ELYMAS] Well, I don't know.
I thought it was a fair split.
-[distant chatter]
-[birds chirping]
He mentioned to me
the thing's called a Lucky Bird.
-[indistinct chatter]
-Really?
[ELYMAS] Hmm. Ruche and I
still haven't agreed on how
to best split the treasure.
We did, however,
decide to sell our items
at the Hall of Broken Grimoires.
Oh?
[♪ ominous music playing]
[inhaling]
-[exhales]
-[coughs]
[SHOPKEEP]
Well, well. You're back.
And with a cute girl this time,
I see.
Is she a friend of yours, kid?
You better
not have sold that book.
[SHOPKEEP]
You don't trust me, do you?
Of course I've still got
the Fang of Smoldering Insanity.
I value my customers' trust,
after all.
How unique.
This is the place
holding your item, Mr. Elymas?
[SHOPKEEP]
She seems like a sweet girl.
Tell me something.
You're not planning
on making her use
that skillbook, are you now?
Not that it's
any of your business,
but no, I would never do that.
It's for me.
Right. Whatever.
Either way,
you're some sort of freak
if you wanna
get your mitts on that thing.
Hmm?
[ELYMAS]
I actually came here today
to have you appraise some items.
Oh? I'm actually stunned
to hear that.
It might sound strange
coming from me,
but you seem too smart
to consider selling
anything here.
[gasps]
I gotta say, this is certainly
quite the surprise.
Two Dazzling Raana
Decorative Blades!
If I'd known
you were such a big shot,
I would've treated you like one
when we first met.
My mistake, kid.
I'm not negotiating
on the price.
[slams]
I'll sell them to you
for 30 million gold.
That's my offer.
Any less, and I'll take them
somewhere else.
[gasps]
[SHOPKEEP] Hmm.
You'll have a hard time
getting that much
at a legitimate shop, newbie.
But sell it here
and you won't have to worry
about rumors spreading
and unwanted attention.
Taking risks
for a little extra gold
isn't worth losing your head.
I'll give you 25 million.
[ELYMAS] What?
Are you kidding me?
I told her
I wasn't going to negotiate,
and she pulls this?
So, what now?
You've gotta admit,
she has a good point
about not attracting attention.
And 25 million gold
is still a whole lot.
Don't fall for it, Ruche.
She'll take advantage
of any weakness that we show.
Oh.
[ELYMAS] 30 million gold
is a high price,
and like she said,
it'll be tough to get that
anywhere else.
Considering the risk,
I could just sell them here.
But if I let her control
the conversation,
she'll negotiate for even less.
I have gold
from selling Magic Stones.
I think I'll just hold on
to the swords
until I get a better deal
for them.
[SHOPKEEP] Shame. Well,
I can't make you do anything
you don't want to do.
But these swords...
aren't why you're here,
are they?
[gasps]
[ELYMAS] I have a skillbook
dropped by a Dreamlord.
I'm thinking about using it.
But if you'll give me
a good price,
I'll consider selling it to you.
[SHOPKEEP] A skillbook? [gasps]
I can't believe
a newbie like you
found one of these things
so quickly.
Keep this up and you--
or actually, the two of you,
are gonna start
gaining a reputation
as heroes around town.
[Ruche whimpers]
Impressive.
And you say you're willing
to part with it, eh?
[ELYMAS]
She's obviously interested.
But how much will she pay?
The current market price
is 20 million gold.
But I'd be risking
both my neck and my business
if I bought this thing from you.
The guild would only give you
seven million gold for it,
and that's only
if they were feeling generous.
You seem skilled,
and since I'm a nice person,
I'll bump up the price
because we might
do business again.
I'll make you an offer of, um,
let me think here, oh,
let's say 14 million.
And then you'll turn around
and sell it
at an insane markup, right?
It's quite easy to find a buyer
for Intermediate Wind Magic.
If you want
to do business again,
then I suggest you give me
no less than 22 million gold.
[grumbles]
[scalding]
-Hot!
-Brat!
I made you
an incredibly generous offer
on a spellbook
you have no intention of using!
And you respond
like a greedy jackass!
You're calling me greedy?!
You're the one selling things
at jacked-up prices,
you crazy old bat!
Geez, talk about the pot
calling the kettle black!
[both growling]
[RUCHE] Um.
-[both grunt]
-[gasps]
I'm sorry,
but the skillbook that he wants,
how much does the Fang
of Smoldering Insanity cost?
You're interrupting.
I'm having fun chewing out
your delusional friend here.
But since you asked,
the price is 55 million gold
for the skillbook he wants.
The market price is only
30 million gold though, Ruche.
She's trying
to take advantage of us.
Whoa. 55 million gold, huh?
I thought I knew what to expect,
but that's still so expensive.
[growls]
Hmm. [gasps]
Excuse me, ma'am?
-Huh?
-Hmm?
I'd like to suggest an offer.
Would you trade that skillbook
and all of these other items,
everything laid before you,
for the Fang
of Smoldering Insanity?
-[gasps]
-Now, hold on.
You interrupted
our negotiations for that?
That's not exactly a fair deal.
But still,
it's not a bad one, either.
I'd be getting rid
of a skillbook
that no one seems to want
in exchange for items
that are easy to sell.
That's a win for me.
[ELYMAS] Ruche's deal
would be good for us.
We still have the payout
from the Magic Stones
and slaying the monsters,
and now on top of that,
we'd have the Fang
of Smoldering Insanity too.
-Listen up, girl.
-[yelps]
You shouldn't interrupt
a merchant
when they're doing business.
But betting on a future hero
isn't all that bad of an idea.
So I accept
the terms of your offer.
Thank you so much!
No! Hold on a second!
You can't do this! If you do,
you won't get your fair share!
I'm perfectly fine with that.
Just think of it
as a thank-you present
from me to you, Mr. Elymas.
Ruche, please! This is way
too much of a thank you.
And what happens
if our next adventure doesn't go
as well as the last one?
Think about it.
What if we have to disband
our party for some reason?
Wait a sec.
[gasps]
You're not planning
to abandon me
anytime soon, are you?
The way you're talking,
I'm starting to think
you're preparing
-for a clean break.
-[ELYMAS] No, I'm not.
I'm just thinking
what if things should go awry.
There's no problem that
we can't handle together!
-[gasps]
-[giggles]
Okay, ma'am!
I say we get this trade done!
And pretty quickly too!
Before he can say anything else!
Good job convincing him, girl.
Don't let him get away.
Hold on to him.
[ELYMAS] What?!
-[slaps]
-[both laugh]
[groans]
[ELYMAS] Why are those two
getting along so well?
-[rain pattering]
-[thunder rumbling]
[♪ mysterious music playing]
[horse snorting]
[prisoners groaning]
[clears throat]
Hmm.
[prisoners groaning]
[panting heavily]
[grunts]
[prisoner 1 screams]
-[slashing]
-[Malice grunting]
[prisoner 2 screams]
[Malice laughs]
-[grunts, laughs]
-[slashing]
[grunting]
-[Malice grunts]
-[nobles whispering]
[Malice grunts, laughs]
[THOMAS] Lady Malice, please!
That's enough!
Lifeforce Transfer has ended!
[WOMAN]
Her methods seem a bit savage.
-[MAN] It's good EXP, but still.
-[WOMAN] Right?
[sighs]
[MALICE]
You may have been exiled,
but you won't go down easily.
I've known that
ever since we were young.
You won't be easy prey.
That's why I need
to take my time with you.
[chuckles softly]
Isn't that right,
my dear little Elymas?
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[ELYMAS] The Fang
of Smoldering Insanity skillbook
is finally mine!
I can't wait to use it!
"Beware of those
who possess this Skill Tree.
Dragging his shattered body,
and letting
his torn tail flutter,
not even the God of Death
dares approach
his unstoppable rampage!"
How did I miss this unsettling
descriptive text?
Next time, "Inescapable Past."
No, wait.
I need to stay grounded.